Why do you need the Kherson region? Well, these are originally Russian lands and the whole of Ukraine is not originally Russian. Kyiv is an original Russian land. Yes, I would say that there is no sense, this is Rus' where Rus' is. Kiev Let it be Ukraine. Hello, I’m listening. Let’s talk normally again today, and I’m normally saying something- then you’re getting angrier and angrier Yes, you’re becoming angrier, well, I’m angry there But my subscribers are not evil, let’s talk to them again The thing is that in Kursk
зачем вам Херсонская
they are hammering seriously they are hammering So you
долбят серьёзно долбят Так вы же ещё 2
told me 2 weeks ago that there is already a
недели мне назад сказали что там уже
boiler there 20,000 people from the joint venture are hammering it are
котёл 20.000 людей из СП его долбят
hammering it Well, when they are hammering then we’ll
долбят Ну вот когда долбят тогда
talk,
поговорим
let’s now sweat on again to the
а давайте давайте сейчас пот на снова на
question we last time had such a good
вопрос мы в прошлый раз так Хорошо
conversation, answer
пообщались поо отвечайте на вопросы
people’s questions  It’s not worth it with you at all since it’s not not
людей с тобой вообще не стоит раз не не
with me but with my subscribers they are
со мной а с моими подписчиками они
normal it’s me
нормальны это я
sleepy Well come on Let’s
сной Ну давай Давайте
So that means Leonid from Belgorod  from the
Так значит Леонид из Белгорода из
Belgorod region in touch Let's
Белгородской области на связи Давайте
ask questions write questions only
задавайте вопросы пишите вопросы только
more or less
более-менее
serious we already had this Inter
серьёзные это у нас уже было Интер
we continue this
ним мы продолжаем эту
series
серию
so angry BBR ask What brand do
так злый ббр спрашивают Какого бренда у
you have this hoodie clothes what
вас это худи одежда какой
brand I don’t know don’t know
бренд не знаю не знаете
so Alex Cosmos asks when you
так Алекс Космос спрашивает когда вы
Ukraine
Украину
grab it Why don’t we need it, don’t
захватите А зачем она нам не нужна не
understand,
нуж поня
asks Or do you eat dill for food? Do you
спрашивает Или вы едите укроп в пищу
eat dill? Do you eat dill?
употребляете укроп употребляют в пищу у
Yes, I understand. Zhanna asks what village are you from
вас Да понял Жанна спрашивает с какой вы
Uspenka and Uspenka  Uspenka Yes, I’ll look
Успенка а Успенка Успенка Да я посмотрю
somewhere like Lisne from Norway Asks
где-то так лисне из Норвегии Спрашивает
you are a
Вы
believer, this is a personal matter, I personally understood
верующий это личное моё дело лично понял
So uh
Так ээ
Alex asks the city of the first fireworks,
Алекс спрашивает город первого салюта
what
это какой
city is it? Well, it’s considered Belgorod or Orel
город Ну считается Белгород или Орёл
understood
понял
So they ask if you don’t need Ukraine,
Так спрашивают если вам не нужна Украина
why did you get into it
зачем вы в неё
that I  I can say about this that
лезли что я могу по этому поводу сказать
in order to ask such questions you need to at
чтобы такие вопросы задавать нужно хотя
least know the topic of the EU. A person
бы тему знать ЕС Челове вот такие
asks such questions, which means he doesn’t know the topic,
вопросы задаёт значит он тему не знает
so what should he say about Teto, he doesn’t
поэтому Ну что ему говорить о тето не
know the cheat
знает чит
climbed and climbed Well, yes  so asks How many digits in the number 1488 are correct Yes, so Max asks Max asks why do you need the Kherson region Well, these are originally Russian lands and the whole of Ukraine is not original Russian Kyiv is an original Russian land Yes, I would say no I mean, this is Rus' where Rus' is Kyiv Let it be will Ukraine not understand then Kiev is already Kherson is originally Russian Kyiv is no longer originally Russian interestingly understood okay Kyiv will be Ukraine Maxim asks when Russia will start
лез взяли и лез Ну да так
conquer
отвоевывать
Alaska never never Roxalana
Аляску никогда никогда Роксалана
Roksolyan asks What is the temperature
роксоляна спрашивает Какая температура
in your basement What is the temperature of you in the basement What is
вас в подвале Что вы так
the temperature
расх ничего не понял Какая температура у
in your basement so much What is the temperature in your basement That you have opened your chest so much
вас в подвале Что вы так раскрыли аж
25 25 liner asks from Norway with a
25 25 линер спрашивает из Норвегии
companion
спутником
vaccinated vaccinated
прививались прививался
once one not Well, I mean twice
один раз один не Ну в смысле два раза
she  same double Well, well, that is, I
она же двойная Ну ну то есть я имею в
mean Yes, one or two so good
виду Да один или два так хорошо
uh I ask in 194 in 1994  we went to
ээ спрашиваю в 194 в 1994 году ездили в
Kharkov
Харьков
I we went to Barbashova to Barbashova for a little thing
я мы за вещичка ездили на барбашову на
I understood
понял
So Alex asks Where did the
Так Алекс спрашивает А куда делись
Russian
русские
comedians go Yes on the
юмористы Да на
spot
месте
uh
ээ
so they ask Why is there no more communism
так спрашивают Почему коммунизма больше
Well, it didn’t exist in principle why
Ну это а его в принципе не было почему
it didn’t exist and didn’t
его Нет его и не
exist
было
asks asking Why Russia
спрашивает спрашивают Зачем Россия
dropped aerial bombs on
сбросила авиабомб на
Belgorod, what can I
Белгород что
say? By the way, this was a couple of years ago. Vmro
сказать А это кстати ещё пару назад вмро
Aleftina asks if he will
Алефтина спрашивает если путя будет
run for another term, if he
баллотироваться ещё на один срок если
survives, you will vote for him.
доживёт будете за него
Well, let’s live  before that
голосовать Ну давайте доживём до этого
Yes, yes, you assess your chances well, he
Да да ты свои шансы хорошо оцениваешь
asks, and Alaska is originally
так спрашивает а Аляска исконно
Russian, yes And so, why didn’t you
русская да А так Почему не
dare, well, at one time they gave it to America,
отва ну в своё время отдали Америке
so they gave it back and gave Crimea to
поэтому те возвратами так а Крым отдали
Ukraine and now it’s
Украине а теперь
a return Well, Alaska was actually sold, and in
возврат Ну Аляску вообще-то продали та
short, Crimea was given to Alaska  now they gave the
там короче Крым отдали Аляску отдали
Crimea back to Alaska no, it’s interesting
теперь Крым назад Аляску нет интересно
not that the Russian Crimea was and
не Крым русский был есть и
will be conquered in
будет его завоевали в
1736 by the German Minich and
1736 году немец миних а 1838
annexed for a long time in 1838  to the Russian
году долго присоединил к Российской
Empire So something
империи Так что то
without
без
So what is your pension Igor asks
Так какая у вас пенсия спрашивает Игорь
like this who do you call your
вот так кого называете своим
national
национальным
hero Nikolai
героем Николая
Gaste so
гасте так
Tatyana asks How long do you
Татьяна спрашивает Как долго вы
plan to stay in the basement How
планируете находиться в подвале Как
long what How long do you plan to
долго что Как долго вы планируете
stay in the
находиться в
basement in a
подвале в
shelter And what am I in the basement  I am Well, you
убежище А что я в подвале нахожусь Ну вы
said that you are in a basement somewhere, you are in a
говорили что вы в подвале где-то вы в
temporary accommodation center Well,
пункте временного размещения А ну
yes, well, no, well, the fact is that
да ну нет ну Дело в том что уже
most of the areas have already been liberated, people are
большинство районов освобождено люди
returning there, but they are not particularly allowed in there
туда возвращаются но туда особо не
because there are shells there  mines there is
пускают потому там снаряды мины там
so much of this stuff that And so people are already
столько этого добра что А так люди уже
slowly
потихоньку
returning, the director of the special plant
возвращаются директор спец завода
asks have you heard the new song of
спрашивает слышали ли вы новую песню
Semyon Slepakov,
Семёна Слепакова
I don’t even know, neither do I,
не я даже не знаю тоже также я тоже не
Luda asks if his grandfather has a woman, no,
Люда спрашивает есть ли у деда баба нету
no, it’s his grandfather who asks, and
нету это дед так э спрашивает а
Finland is Russian  territory asks
Финляндия русская территория спрашивает
Sasha Yes, no, not Russian,
Саша Да нет не русская
so Olesya asks Did
так Олеся спрашивает Шапочку из фольги
you make a hat out of tinfoil? What kind of hat is made from
себе шапочку что из
tinfoil? Why? Well, I don’t know, uh, Elena
фольги Зачем Ну не знаю так э Елена
Benson from California asks  why are
Бенсон из Калифорнии спрашивает почему
the Russians so rude and ill-mannered
русские такие грубые и невоспитанные
I
я
find it difficult to answer him on this question
затрудняюсь что ли ему по этому вопросу
Uh-huh So uh they ask about Belarus, which is originally
Угу Так ээ спрашивают о Белорусь исконно
Russian and then you will conquer it too
русская да то её будете тоже завоёвывать
yes So n 777 asks you how many
да Так н 777 спрашивает вас сколько
flats are in the B major scale
бемолей в гамме си [__]
what scale How many flats are in the B
какой гам Сколько бемолей в гамме си
major scale A  that there is such a gamma since I don’t know
[__] А что есть такая гамма раз не знаю
ask him if he has such a gamma 777
спросить у него есть такая гамма 777 вас
asks you Or is there such a gamma Bo  I don’t
спрашивает Или есть такая гамма Бо я не
know the evil bar
знаю злый бар
asks Yes, the evil Beaver asks
спрашивает Да злый Бобёр спрашивает
why you think that
почему вы считаете что исконно может
someone’s land can originally determine in the modern
определять чья-то земля в современном
world, well,
мире ну
Donetsk Kuban Lugansk they were
Донецк Кубань Луганск они как были
Russian, so they remain Russian even
русские так они остаются русскими ещё и
before the revolution and in the 19th century these were all
до революции и в 19 веке это всё были
Russian lands so  that And the question is Where to
русские земли так что А вопрос Откуда
consider the primordial For example, the
считать исконно Вот например
Tatar-Mongols will consider that
татаро-монголы да будут считать что
Moscow is their ancestral territory,
Москва - это ихняя исконная территория
this is their problem, so only the
это ихние проблемы так это только
Russians can consider their IP territories to be
русские могут считать свои территории ИС
equestrian And  others and there Russians live there,
конными А другие а там русские живут там
not Tatars live there Russians live so
же не татары живут там русские живут так
well
хоро
Russians are originally Russian territory
русские искона русская территория
Yes, but Russians live there no tricky idea
Да а там русские живут нет хитрая идея
Yes, and the Bashkirs are like Whose Land What
Да а башкиры - это как Чья Земля Какая
Isko Bashkor Bashkor originally Bashkor Xia
Иско башкира башкор исконно башкор ся
Earth Yes, these are Russian lands I understand Yes so
Земля Да это русские земли понял Да так
so look, then the Mongols believe that
так смотри так тогда монголы считают что
Moscow is their ancestral lands, so I
Москва - это ихние исконные земли так я
can think that our New York is also
могу посчитать что и нью-йорк наш тоже
Russian  don’t just look Keep in mind
русский так не просто смотри Имей в виду
that’s where the difference is, you
вот где у вас разница вы
think that these are your lands, they
считаете что Это ваши земли они когда-то
were once yours Yes,
были ваши Да
why Well, as
почему Ну как
always Remember the battle in the revolution for
всегда Вспомни сражение в революции за
Catherine the
Екатерина
Sla Well, you always say if you
сла Ну ты говоришь всегда если ты
say yourself that Crimea was captured in the 10th
говоришь сам что Крым был захвачен в X
century  Well, that means it’s not always before.
веке Ну значит не всегда До этого была
Before that there was a golden rada. Before that there was the
там золотая рда До этого была Империя
Russian Empire of Khan. What is the Empire?
хана Российская Что такое Империя
It’s all the
Империя она все
seizures of foreign lands from this, yes, the
захваты чужие Земли из это да Империя
Genghis Khan Empire also works, then why Why
Чингисхана также дела то почему Почему
Russian?  the empire expanded, captured the
Российская империя расширилась захватила
Crimea, look correctly, why do you
Крым правильно то смотрите А почему вы
think that these are your ancestral,
считаете что Это ваши исконные они
ancestral Mongolian
исконные монгольские
territories, and who lives on these lands?
территории А кто на этих землях
Crimean Tatars
живёт Крымские татары
rda You’re talking about Crimea. I’m talking about everything,
рда Ты про Крым говоришь Я про всё
and about Tatarstan, and what’s interesting about you is
говорю и про Татарстан и у вас интересно
that Russia is your primordial
то что Россия - Это ваши исконные
territories Yes, but what’s more, in short, it was all
территории Да а то что короче тут было
there Mongolia These are not your ancestral territories Well, it
там Монголия всё Это не ваши исконные Ну
was what was and is not St. Petersburg -
было что была и нет санкт-петербург -
these are the ancestral Swedish
это исконные шведские
territories  did they conquer this or that the original ones or did
территории отвоевали то то исконные или
you
вы
conquer them? And I understand. You Russians have a
отвоевали А я понял У вас у русских
logic for everything that they conquered and not the
логика всё что они завоевали т не
original ones. I understood the whole formula absolutely correctly.
исконные понял Совершенно правильно всё
So,
формулу понял Да так
uh, is Grandfather ready to surrender to an
ээ готов ли Дед сдаться в плен
American mercenary in exchange for a burger
американскому наёмника в обмен на бургер
and cola? Well, that’s a funny
и колу Ну шуточный такой
question. Well.  let Shotik move on
вопрос Ну пускай Шотик дальше
Yes so Why do you always have a hood on
Да так Почему у вас всегда капюшон на
your head
голове
I
Мне так
like it so much People NVA asks Should
нравится Люди НВА спрашивает Должна ли
Russia return the historical
Россия вернуть полякам исторические
lands of
земли
Kaliningrad to the Poles that Kalin to the Poles  return
Калининград что Калин полякам вернуть
Kaliningrad
Калининград
And whose Land is this? Well, this is not your
А чья это Земля Ну это же не ваша
ancestral
исконная
Well, then again
Ну так это во время опять возникает
the question arises: how did Kaliningrad get to Russia? You
вопрос как Калининград попал в Россию вы
captured the Polish ancestral Lands,
захватили польские исконные Земли
where are the Polish lands Yes, the Polish Czech lands,
где польские земли Да польские чешский
in general, there is
вообще там
Krolevets, where the Polish lands were captured
кролевец где польские земли захвачены
Kaliningrad, so Whose Land was this?
Калининград так Чья это Земля была
German  The land is not Polish nuno
немецкая Земля не польская нуно
Polish So okay let's move
польская Так ладно едем
on so the question is Poland is also part of
дальше так вопрос Польша тоже часть
Poland was also in the Russian Empire
Польши была тоже в Российской империи
this is also primordial  The Russian land
это тоже исконная русская земля
was Russian, but
была русская да
Poland moved away - this is the original Russian
отошла Польша - это исконная русская
land Yes,
земля Да сейчас
not now. So wait. And why
нет Так подождите А почему Херсон она
was Kherson part of the Russian Empire, and
была в составе Российской империи так а
Kherson? Then why is the original Russian
Херсон Тогда почему исконно русская
land, too, now no, the Russians have always lived
земля тож тоже сейчас нет всегда жили
and
русские и сейчас
live now, this one asks, even if you’ve
живут сей спрашивает каже что вы
finished  his life in a temporary
закончили свою жизнь в пункте временного
accommodation center No, it doesn’t seem like a wild nerd
размещения Нет не кажется дикий задрот
asks why they didn’t touch Crimea until
спрашивает почему не трогали Крым до
2014, well, because the
года ну потому что случился
Maidan coup happened and we need to
Майдан государственный переворот и надо
come to you  that is, in Ochakov they began to
пошло к вам то есть в Очакове начали
build an American base right away
строить базу американскую прям сразу же
immediately during the Maidan, they began to build an
сразу же во время Майдана начали строить
American base,
базу американскую
later they began to build Berdyansk bases, which
позже начали строить Бердянские базы что
was written into the Constitution in the Ukrainian
в Конституцию записали в украинскую
entry into NATO. Yes, no, so wait,
вступление в НАТО Да нет Так подождите
so, uh, Crimea was captured in February of the
Так ээ Крым захватили в феврале
fourteenth year, when the Maidan was still going on
четырнадцатого года когда ещё Майдан шёл
Well, why aren’t there any bases yet, no
Ну так а почему ещё никаких не баз ни
question, we didn’t just take him, we captured him, there
вопрос мы не просто взяли его захватили
must have been some reason, I don’t
наверное же причина была какая-то не
know, we’re on the contrary  we want to join
знаю мы наоборот это мы хотим вступить в
NATO because Russia is attacking us
НАТО потому что Россия на нас нападает
Okay, let's move on Well, who doesn't want to Yes,
Ладно едем дальше Ну кому не хотим Да
look, we were neutral Noah Roma
смотри мы были нейтральной ной Рома
asks if you watched the channels of
спрашивает просматривали ли вы каналы
Zolkin and the Apostle, dialogues with
золкина и апостола диалоги с
prisoners of war, what do you think about these
военнопленными что думаете про эти
stories without
истории без
understanding, so the question Aristarchus asks and
поняти так вопрос Аристарх спрашивает а
Moscow From  who
Москву От кого
was conquered or is it also primordial it is
отвоевали или она тоже исконная это
primordial
искон
[music]
[музыка]
Russians Sakhalin Russian lands
русские Сахалин русская землях
Russian
русская
land I think that no it is not even now
земля думаю что нет она и сейчас не
Russian Dagestan the original Russian land
русская Дагестан исконно русская земля
Dagestan yes Why do Russian
Дагестан да А почему там что русские
people
люди
live there it was part of Turkey or the
живут она была в составе Турции или
Russian Empire and Kazakhstan was
Российской империи так и Казахстан был в
part of the Russian Empire
составе Российской империи
when
когда
hello when during the Russian
здравствуйте когда во время Российской
Empire
империи
when this year there was Kazakhstan Well where
когда в сем году был Казахстан Ну а где
was it something  you're confused dear What are you
был что то ты запутался родной Что ты за
And where Which is good e Kazakhstan was in
А где Какая хорошо э Казахстан был в
which country in 1917 it was on its
какой стране в 1917 году он был сам по
own and it was called
себе так и назывался
Kazakhstan Well, I think
Казахстан Ну думаю что
so And in 1922 it entered  Soviet
да А в 1922 году он вошёл в Советский
Union
Союз
Quite interestingly understood well and Latvia
Довольно интересно понял хорошо а Латвия
Lithuania Estonia is a native Russian
Литва Эстония - это исконно русские
territory no So they were in the
территории нет Так они же были в
Russian
Российской
Empire they were not in the Russian Empire
империи не были они в Российской империи
Well
Ну
hello they were part of the
здравствуйте они были в составе
Soviet Union this was already in the thirty-
Советского Союза это уже в тридцать
ninth year as part of the Soviet Union
девятом году в составе Советского Союза
And before that  they were in the Russian Empire, the
А до этого они были в Российской империи
city of
город
Vil What
Виль Как
was the name of the Polish Land of the Poles and
назывался была польская Земля поляки а
Stalin took it and annexed it to the Soviet
Сталин взял и присоединил к Советскому
Union and the wine became vi and so
Союзу и вину стал ви и так
[music]
[музыка]
Dale Okay I
Дале Ладно я
Grandfather has an overload of flats, this is something termi is
у деда перегруз бемолями это чтото терми
musical in
музыкален
front major, it doesn’t
переда [__] она не
have a major, it doesn’t
имеет [__] не
have a ball, put it like this, Elena
имеет шарика поставил так э Елена
Mostovaya Asks if you accept the idea
Мостовая Спрашивает допускаете ли мысль
that you are just
что вы просто
old, who uses historical myths
старый который историческими мифами
to justify the murder of people in Ukraine,
оправдывает убийство людей в Украине
whom the murder of people in
кого убийство людей в
Ukraine, I made it difficult to do anything about this
Украине я затрудняли что-либо по этому
About
поводу
that, it’s a
го так
good question, announce the entire list of
Хороший вопрос огласите весь список
ancestral Russian lands so that we
исконных русских земель чтобы Мы
understand where the primordially Russians are, where the non-
понимали где исконно русские где не
primordial ones are now scattering Well, at least in
искон сейчас разбегаемся Ну хотя в
principle  is it possible Odessa Nikolaev
принципе можно Одесса Николаев
Dnipropetrovsk is not in Ukraine It is clear
днипропетровск не в Украине Понятно
except for
кроме
Ukraine Well, the Russian Empire was where it was,
Украины Ну Российская империя где была
well, I don’t know
ну я не знаю
there Georgia is the original Russian lands
там Грузия - это исконно русские земли
Yes, of course, Ermak Khabarov opened
Да конечно открывал Ермак Хабаров
Magilan VS, it was
магилан ВС это были
Russian, of course,
русс конечно
hair dryer PP what kind of
фен ПП какой
Magilan, well, such as Fernando
магилан ну такой какой Фернандо
Magilan, of course it’s under PPP  what kind of
магилан конечно кру подо ППП какой
Magilan
магилан
trip was it not only he who
путешествие не только он совершал
traveled? Not what kind of Magilan was there in Russia?
путешестви Не а что за магилан в России
Well, because it was there  Okay, let's move
был Ну тому что там был Ладно поехали
on Who are the Russians asking Gri
дальше Кто такие русские спрашивают Гри
Russian is Russian Russian is
русский - это русский русский - это
Russian to understand recursion You must
русский чтобы понять рекурсию Надо
first understand recursion I understood the joke
сначала понять рекурсию понял прикол
so in the World Cup the mystery of the Russian soul is a matchmaker
так в ЧМ загадочность русской души сва
I'm on the riddle how
Я на
she thinks and
загадке как она считает так и
lets go
пускает
So what does it mean
Так что означает
from time immemorial here is a person born he was born  was
исконно исконно вот человек родился он
originally born, let’s say, in Belgorod.
исконно родился допустим в Белгороде Вот
This will originally be his land and he is originally
это исконно будет его земля и он исконно
Belgoro, that is,
белгоро то есть
at first, as it was Russian, so it is
сначала как она была русская так она
considered ikor
считается икор
[music]
[музыка]
russ did you know that Russia nala
русс знаете ли вы что Россия нала
where they attacked
куда напали на
Ukraine on Crimea on
Украину на Крым на
Crimea actually Russian and it wouldn’t have been
Крым вообще-то Российска а ще бы не было
only in Sevastopol only in
только в Севастополе только была в
some
отдельных
places Good question Why didn’t
местах Вопрос хороший Почему ри иди не
they get to Moscow
дошли до Моск
Didn’t they get to Moscow and why are they going to Moscow
не дошли до Москвы а что они на Москву
Well, where did they go, where did they bring
шли Ну они а куда они принесли
the writing Cyril and
письменность Кирилл и
Methodius Where to Russia to Russia This is in
Мефодий Куда в Россию в Россию Это в
what year Well, I don’t remember then
каком году Ну гото я не помню тогда
Russia didn’t exist yet When  Cyril lived Well, I mean the Russian Empire What kind of Russia doesn’t exist then you still have to look, I’ll tell you for sure, Cyril and Methodius lived like this in the 9th century, I won’t say In what century in the 9th century Cyril and Methodius lived And where did they live? Here They were actually Bulgarians, yes. So Cyril lived like this from 827 to 869, even before Rus' was baptized. Yes, his older brother Methodius lived with
России ещё не было Когда жили Кирилла Ну
815 to 885 they died, even Vladimir didn’t baptize Rus', to which Russian empire did they bring the initial letters? Well, I find it difficult to say anything about this. Why did they bring it to me anyway? No, well, you are now writing Cyrillic letters in Russian Yes, of course Where did they get into the Russian language? What about Cyril Methodius Yes, but Cyril and Methodius Look, they lived before the prince  Vladimir while Prince Vladimir baptized Rus' Yes, before that they had already died so there was no Moscow then Moscow will appear 3 Centuries after the death of Cyril and Methodius then where Cyril and Methodius brought the initial letters So what do you want to say that under Ivan the Terrible and under Peter the Cyrillic alphabet was already written Well, look, Ivan the Terrible was 6 centuries after Cyril and Methodius and
вот Владимира пока князь Владимир
they wrote in Cyrillic
писали кириллицей
Yes, you’re native, you’re native, you
Да что-то ты родной что-то ты родной не
’re saying the wrong thing. Well, look, Cyril and
то говоришь Ну смотри ну Кирилл и
Methodius. But look, the verb was no longer there
мефодии Но это смотри там глаголь уже не
under Peter; in short, for sure, yes. Well,
было при Петре короче точно да Ну так
under Peter, under willow, the Cyrillic alphabet was also
при Петре при ива кирилица была и
Old Russian. Ancient language, which is
старорусский Древний язык какой
Old Russian? Ancient  the language of
старорусский Древний язык
the church was written in Cyrillic or what
церков так писали кириллицей или чем
Cyrillic was written in
кириллицей писали
yes Well okay Well look Kirill Cyril and
да Ну хорошо Ну смотри Кири Кирилл и
Methodius Yes perished  ended their lives in the
Мефодий Да погиб закончили свою жизнь в
1st century of Moscow Moscow will appear in 3
I веке Москвы Москва появится через 3
years
лет
the question Where did Cyril and Methodius bring
вопрос Куда принесли Кирилл и Мефодий
their
свои
writings? I don’t know where they
письмена я не знаю куда они
brought them, well, I do
принесли ну так
n’t understand, okay, let’s move
не с понял ладно едем
on, but it was cool that
дальше но это было прикольно что в
Cyril and Methodius brought this to the Russian Empire,
Российскую империю принесли Кирилл и
I haven’t seen anything like this yet  I heard this
Мефодий такого я ещё не слышал это Ну
Well, I’m asking Peter the Great
так я же спрашиваю Пётр Первый кириллице
wrote in Cyrillic No,
писал Нет ну
yes, I’m sure
да уверен
Yes, it’s clear and the
Да понятно и и
church letters are also Kili in Cyrillic
церковный буквы тоже Кили кириллицей
written
писались
Danya yes Previously, it was Glagolitic alphabet, then they already
Даня да Раньше было глаголица потом уже
wrote in Cyrillic Yes, it’s clear So,
писали кириллицей Да понятно Так
uh, the question is, are you registered with
ээ вопрос стоите ли вы на учёте у
a psychiatrist? Well, you don’t have to answer that,
психиатра Ну такой можете не отвечать
yes, yes, of course,
дада да конечно
yes, yes, yes, so Why do many Belgorod residents
так угу так Почему многие белгородцы
speak Ukrainian from
разговаривают на украинском языке из
Israel,
Израиля вам
a question for you Well, because Ukraine is close
вопрос Ну потому что Украина близка
because  Yes, actually, that’s how long I’ve been in
потому Да вообще-то я вот сколько в
Belgorod.
Белгороде
Well, in Ukrainian. I haven’t
Ну на украинском языке Вообще никого не
heard anyone speak surzhik.
слыхал на суржике балакаю
Yes, and in Kursk I speak surzhik.  balaka What is that
Да и в Курске на суржике балака Что есть
is, well, Surzhik is Borg asking if you
то есть ну Суржик это Борг спрашивает
would like to live until the collapse of the Russian
хотели бы дожить до развала Российской
Federation No, would
Федерации Нет не хотел
you like to help the Russian army with money? I’m
помогаете ли вы деньгами российской
helping
помогаю
So let’s write questions to grandfather So
Так давайте пишите вопросы деду Так
why are you sitting in chat roulette
зачем сидите в чат рулетке спрашивает
Bogdan asks, here he is sitting with me, why am I sitting
Богдан вот у меня сидит че зачем я сижу
in roulette  And why are you sitting in the roulette table
в рулетке А ты Зачем сидишь в рулет
right away
сразу
that man is rolling he looks at me
тот человек рулет он смотрит меня
who is sitting in the roulette table they
который сидит в рулетке они вас
ask you why you are sitting what are you
спрашивают зачем вы сидите что вы вот
here I met you  roulette And you
вот я тебя встретил рулетке А ты мне
ask me a question I’m sitting ru And I’m asking
задашь вопро Я сижу ру А я спрашиваю
you Why are you sitting yes I’m the thing is I For
тебя Ты Зачем сидишь да я дело в том я В
scientific purposes I’m a scientist I’m researching the
научных целях я учёный я исследую
behavior of
поведение
deviations researching talking
девиации исследовать беседовать
telling I’m also researching Understand everything We’re
рассказывать я тоже исследую Поня всё Мы
like two super scientists so Vladimir
как два учёных супер так Владимир
says Because
говорит Потому что
Bel  Yes, look, Vladimir
Бел Да смотри Владимир интересно
asks interestingly, speak. He says that Kursk and
спрашивает говори Он говорит что Курск и
Belgorod are originally Ukrainian
Белгород - это исконно украинские
lands, where is this, who is this, Vladimir?  from
земли где это кто Это Владимир из
Israel says Well, I understand, and who Where is
Израиля говорит Ну я понимаю а кто Где
it visible? We all see these are our
это видно видно Всё мы видим это наши
ancestral lands, we believe that is, I am
исконные Земли мы считаем то есть Я
Ukrainian No, you are somehow incomprehensible
украинец Нет вы непонятный какой-то
at all. You live on our ancestral lands,
вообще Вы живёте на наших землях
yes, the new one asks. Judging by his answers,
да овая спрашивает Судя по его ответам
he doesn’t know anything about  history, why does
он ничего не знает по истории почему же
he declare with such confidence about the
он с такой уверенностью заявляет про
ancestral
исконные
lands that what what must be answered Well,
земли что что что отвечать надо Ну
answer Why what must be answered what I do
ответьте Почему что отвечать надо чего
n’t know or what, is it so evil evil BBR
не знаю что ли так злой злый ббр
asks Where is the Russian Republic
спрашивает А где русская республика
Why is there a Republic of Tatarstan Chechnya
Почему есть Республика Татарстан Чечня
Why not
Почему нет русской Республики русской
there is no Russian Republic, there
Республики Татарстана нету почему есть
is no Russian Republic of Tatarstan,
республика есть республика Татарстана Да
why is there a republic, there is a republic of Tatarstan?
почему русской нет Республики у русской
Why is there no Russian Republic? The Russian Republic Why there shouldn’t be a Russian Why do
Почему не долж быть русской Ну почему у
all peoples have Republics? And the Russians
всех народов есть Республики А у русских
don’t have their own
нет своей
republic, for some reason we have a republic
республики почему-то у нас республика
razr No, this is everyone, the republic is everyone
разр Нет это всех республика это всех
country Russia No Russia is not a country of
страна Россия Нет Россия - это не страна
Russians it is a country of multinational
русских это страна многонационального
people Russia is a
народа Россия это
region and Tatarstan is part of the region
регион а Татарстан - это часть региона
Chechnya is part of the region see Lada Coast
Чечня часть региона смотрите Лада Кост
asks who is to blame for  Katyn
спрашивает кто виноват в катынское
Tragedies Well, part of the UPA speaks directly And
Трагедии Ну уж прямо говорит часть упа А
mostly mine Hey hello, this means
в основном мину Эй алло это имеет в виду
when the Soviet government
когда советское правительство
shot Polish prisoners Katyn
расстреляла польских пленных катыни
what
какой
UPA is this Smolensk region what UPA
упа это Смоленщина какой упа
and what is evidence, too, yes, well,
а что есть доказательства тоже да ну
Medvedev admitted back in the tenth year, like
Медведев ещ в десятом году признал типа
they apologized that he admitted  in the
принесли извинение что что признался в
tenth year, like, the Soviet archives were declassified.
десятом году типа рассекретили архивы
Yes, they admitted that
советские Да признали что был расстрел
these Polish officers were shot.
этих польских офицеров
Well, I won’t say  anything
Да ну я не буду утверждать что-либо по
about this and then when the plane with the
этому поводу а потом же Когда самолёт с
Polish government
польским правительством
was blown up when on the anniversary of the tragedy
взорвали когда они на годовщину трагедии
who blew it up
кто взорвал
Well, you’re a historian, you want to say that this is a
Ну ты же историк ты хочешь скать что это
modern story
современный сюжет
Yes, I’m asking you who who blew up
Да я вас спрашиваю кто кто взорвал
the plane it crashed into a pine tree into a pine tree I
самолёт он врезался в сосну в сосну
understood
понял
of course
конечно
so  Dnb asks if you know the
так днб спрашивает знаете ли вы
Ukrainian language No, you don’t want to He doesn’t want to
украинский язык Нет ты не хо Не хочет он
Denmark asks are you ashamed in front of your
Дания спрашивает ва стыдно перед
Ukrainian friends? You’ve often
знакомыми украинцами Вы же раньше часто
been to
были в
Ukraine before, you’re ashamed that you’re ashamed in front of
Украине стыдно что стыдно ли вам перед
familiar
знакомыми
Ukrainians For what For the fact that your country is
украинцами За что За то что ваша страна
bombing
бомбит
them like this then I have a question And
их так у меня тогда возникает вопрос А
what did Ukraine forget in the Kursk land
что Украина забыла в Курской земле
liberating its ancestral
освобождает свои исконные
territories went on course to liberate
территории пошла в курс да освобождать
its ancestral lands Well, well, yes, they’re hammering,
свои исконные земли Да ну вот да долбят
this will all end How often do
на этом всё закончится Как часто
you watch TV asks  Maria
смотрите телевизор спрашивает Мария
rarely, I feel sorry for spending time sitting and
редко мне жалко время тратить сидеть и
staring
пялится
like
вот
this, what do you think if the capital of Ukraine
так что думаете если столицу Украины
is moved to Belgorod or Kursk,
перенесут в Белгород или Курск
excuse the expression, your character won’t crack I
извините за выражение хар не треснет Я
think when they move it, yours will
думаю когда перенесут у вас треснет
definitely crack Danya What  this is chauvinism asks
точно Даня Что такое шовинизм спрашивает
Victor I don’t know I don’t want to answer Lisna
Виктор не знаю я отвечать не хочу лисне
from Norway asks What
из Норвегии спрашивает Какие книги
modern books do you read or only
современные вы читаете или только
old ones I read mostly Russian classics
старые читаю в основном классику русскую
[music]
[музыка]
which Russian Well for example
какую русскую Ну например
what
ну какие
works do I love Kuprin I love
произведения люблю Куприна люблю
Tolstoy
Толстова
Lermontov what books from Kuprin have
Лермонтова что из Куприна
you read Garnet
читали Гранатовый
bracelet
браслет
pit duel  Well,
яма поединок Ну и так
yes, Kuprin wrote a hole when he lived in my
дае Куприн написал яму когда жил в моём
city in Khmelnitsky Proskura, I don’t
городе в Хмельницком проскура это я не
know, so
знаю так
uh here,
ээ
here, here, want to
тук-тук-тук хотите
go home  And who doesn’t
домой А кто домой не
want to go home the question
хочет вопрос
uh Russia dropped on Kharkov if at least
ээ Россия сбросила на Харьков кабы хоть
one tank was knocked out in
один танк подбили в
Kharkov a tank factory was destroyed in Kharkov
Харькове в харкове разрушен танковый
Well, they are throwing
завод Ну а вот на жилые дома бросают
bombs on residential buildings on residential buildings kindergartens Why does
бомбы на жилые дома садики Поче это у
someone have a sick imagination Yeah I understand
кого-то больное воображение Ага понял
sick imagination so wild nerd
больное воображение так дикий задрот
asks why Russians consider Bandera
спрашивает почему Бандеры считают
a Nazi.
нацистом
And I don’t think he’s a Nazi, well,
россияне А что вроде нацист не считаю ну
why do you think Bandera is a
вы почему вот вы считаете бандеру
Nazi? I don’t think he’s a gang at all.
нацистом Я его вообще никак не считаю
I have a question: who is he by
кто для вас банда У меня вопрос он по
nationality,
национальности
who is he an Austrian, what is an Austrian Bandera?
кто он австриец был что австриец Бандера
Yes, he was born in the Austro-Hungarian
Да он родился в австро-венгерской
Empire, he is all an original Austrian, in what
Империи всё он исконный австриец в каком
place was he born in the village of Stary
месте он родился в селе старый
Ugnev, that village of Stary Ugnev, well,
угнев что селе старый угнев ну
Izha
ИЖа
Gorodni, whose Land would it be,
городни Это чья Земля бы
Polish
польская
Land, uh, Poland  Poland did not exist then,
Земля э разго Польши не было тогда
after the collapse of the
Польша появилась после распада
Russian Empire, the Austro-Hungarian
Российской Империи австро-венгерской
Empire
империи
was restored again, look,
восстановилась ещё раз смотри
before the First World War, there
до первой мировой войны государства
was no state of Poland  it was divided then there was a
Польши не было её разделили тогда было
big partition of Poland and Russia Austria
большой раздел Польши да Россия Австрия
Hungary And so on it was
Венгрия И так дальше это была
Austria-Hungary when Bandera was born he
австро-венгрия когда родился Бандера он
was born in Hungary not in
родился в Венгрии не в
Poland Well, I won’t argue, I’m just out of
Польше Ну я не буду спорить я вот ради
interest now, right now this is 300 years,
интереса сейчас вот прямо это 300 лет
your Bandera is not needed No no  not now
ваш Бандера не нужен Не нене не сейчас
look I know him and I don’t want to know Pan
смотри я его знать и знать не хочу Пан
Bandera Now you will recognize our Stepan
Бандера Сейчас вы узнаете нашего Степана
Bandera I only know one thing that he
бандеру Я знаю только одно что у него
had three theses kill the communist kill the
было три тезиса убей коммуниста убей
ryakh  kill a Jew, look, it means Stepan
ряха убей еврея смотрите значит Степан
Andreevich Bandera was born in the village of old
Андреевич Бандера родился в селе старый
Ugri in Kalush Povet
Угры в калушский Повет
kingdom of gocha and oxen
королевство гочи и волами
Austro-Ugric in
австро-угорщина в
Austria-Hungary Well, in Austria-Hungary, yes, Austro-
австро-венгрии Ну в австро-венгрии да
Hungary would have been Austro-Hungary, then the
австро-венгрия бы австро-венгрия была то
Ukrainian read it to you completely,
полностью украинец
he was born in Austro-Hungary  Hungary he was
он родился в австро-венгрию он
talking about the Austro-Hungarians
австро-венгерского поводу разговаривали
you spoke Ukrainian  No, I said, he’s
ты говорил украинец Нет я говорил он
Ukrainian, he said, that’s why he’s Ukrainian, yes,
Укра он сказал поэтому он украинец да да
after the collapse of the Austro-Hungarian Empire, it was
после развала австро-венгерской империи
gone and he says, Let us, Let’s be
не стало и он говорит Давайте мы Давайте
part of
часть
Austro-Hungary, I’ll say that Bandera
австро-венгрии буду говори что Бандера
is not in Ukraine astrong, he’s an
не Украине астронг говорите он
astron astron, he’s not Ukrainian. Well, that means he’s not in
астрон астрон не украинец Ну значит не
Ukraine, of course, he’s not Ukrainian.  they're like
Украине конечно не украинец им как у
him n yes Steph Stepan
него н да стеф Степан
Stepan Austro-Hungarian name Come on,
Степан Австро венгерское имя Да давай
Ukrainians, let's move on Bandera
украинцы давай так едем дальше Бандера
Pavel  asks how many doubles
Павел спрашивает сколько двойников у
Vladimir Putin has, can you die?  I
Владимира Путина умереть
already said about this: Ukraine began to build
поводу уже сказал Украина начала строить
military bases in Berdyansk in Ochakov, yes there
военные базы в Бердянске в Очакове да
was such a thing, I don’t know a single
было такое дело не знаю ни одной
NATO base  I see how you don’t
натовской базы не виже историю как ты не
know history. Well, why are you lying? Well, look!
знаешь Ну что ты брешешь Ну ну посмотри
Open up what happened in Ochakov, what happened before?
Открой что было в Очакове что было бе
Why during the Second World War
так Почему во время Второй мировой войны
there were Ukrainian and Belarusian fronts, And where
были фронта украинский белорусский А где
was the Russian front?
был русский фронт А
Why and
зачем а
what, and there were four Ukrainian fronts, that
что а было четыре украинских фронта это
doesn’t mean that  there, only Ukrainians
не значит что там одни украинцы
fought like that. Well, why wasn’t there
воевали так Ну а почему не было
a Russian? Why was it called Ukrainian?
русского Почему назывался украинский
Belarusian
белорусский
wasn’t Russian yet. Why
русского не было был ещ и пно А почему
wasn’t there a Russian? Why?  calling Well, why did they call And
было Зачем называ Ну почему называли А
why did they call Belarusian and Ukrainian
зачем назвали белорусский и украинский
Well, that’s what they called Why didn’t they call
Ну так назвали А почему не назвали
Russian Why
русский
look like that Anna Boyka says that my grandfather
так смотрите Анна Бойка говорит что дед
misses me that’s why he comes to
скучает за мной поэтому приходит в
Roulette, it’s
Рулетку это
true, how do you
правда так
feel about the Baltic country of
как относитесь к Балтийской стране
Latvia, what do you think about its attitude towards
Латвии что думаете об её отношении к
Russia they ask  Well, they have a bad attitude towards
России спрашивают ну относятся они к
Russia.
России
They
Плохо они
grew up on freebies. The Soviet Union
выросли на халяве Советский Союз им
gave them everything. They grew up on freebies and
давал всё они выросли на халяве и
that’s why it went on and on
поэтому там пошло пошло и пошло
Europeans Europeans Here they are  the Europeans
европейцы европейцы Вот они европейцы им
gave them ROSI The Soviet Union gave everything there was the
РОСИ Советский Союз всё дал там был
VF Inter plant and the Atomic station,
завод ВФ Интер и станция Атомная чего
what they didn’t build there The Soviet Union So uh What do you do besides
эээ Чем занимаетесь помимо
chatroulette Well, actually, I have
чатрулетке Ну вообще-то у меня дел
enough things to do Well, for example, a vegetable garden, a
достаточно Ну например огород
vegetable garden, a barn, I walk
огород сараю гуляю
enough, there’s enough communication, So
достаточно общение есть Так что
what’s the question?  Why did you build everything in
так А вопрос Почему вы всё строили в
Latvia, Belarus, Ukraine, but
Латвии в Беларуси в Украине а в России
didn’t build it in Russia? Why did you build it in all these
не строили зачем вы строили в этих всех
republics? Yes, that’s all it was
республиках Да вот было такое всё
they built in Kazakhstan and Tajikistan,
строили и в Казахстане и в Таджикистане
Uzbekistan in Kyrgyzstan, they built the Soviet
Узбекистане в киргизи строили советские
Republics on the outskirts And they built them in their own country And
Республики на окраине А у себя строили А
now the most important question Look,
теперь самый главный вопрос Смотрите
if you have no longer had the Soviet Union for 33
если вы вот Советского Союза уже нету 33
years,
года
you spent 70 years building the Armed Forces of Belashki for all other
вы 70 лет строили ВС белашки всем другим
republics, now these Republics
республикам теперь эти Республики
have been disconnected, what do you need  What has prevented
отсоединили что же вам мешает эти 33
us from building all this for these 33 years is
года у себя всё это
that we actually have everything in
строить что у нас вообще-то есть всё в
Russia, in Russia we have everything And we are building  I understand
России в России есть всё И мы строим
what we’re not building. Well,
Поня чего мы только не строим Ну а
why don’t you build new factories, why is
почему Новые заводы не строите почему
everything being built there and new factories are
там всё строится и Новые заводы всё
being built on I got it Question and
строится у на Понял Вопрос е интерес
also look at the interest if during the Soviet
тоже смотрите если во время Советского
Union Russia Belash Armed Forces built all
Союза Россия Белаш ВС строила всем
the republics and then why the Republics
республикам да то почему Республики от
don’t want the Republics to unite
соединились Республики не хотят
return to the Soviet Union And the
возвращаться в Советский Союз А
only Russia that built everything for everyone
единственная Россия которая всем Всё
wants the restoration of the Soviet
строила хочет восстановление Советского
Union What is the Paradox And who said that
Союза В чём Парадокс А кто сказал что
Russia wants the restoration of the Soviet
Россия хочет восстановление советского
wants all these
хочет вот эти все
territories are nonsense, don’t tell your lies
территории бред не несите вра своё
just  somehow interesting, yes, the poor guy
просто как-то интересно да бедолаг и
wants to build everyone again So do you
всех хочет снова чтобы строить Так вы
miss Soviet times,
скучаете по советским временам
Jaan asks
спрашивает яан к
you No, I don’t miss Well, I don’t
вам Нет не скучаю Ну не
miss So I only remember what
скучаю Так я вспоминаю только то что
happened in the Soviet Union, my parents
было в Советском Союзе мои родители
got a free
получили бесплатно
apartment, I got a free
квартиру получил я бесплатное
education, free medicine,
образование медицина бесплатная
not  I remember how I took a ticket from
не запомнилось как я взял путёвку из
Moscow along the Moscow Canal along the Volga
Москвы по Московскому каналу по Волге
to Astrakhan and back, it was a
дошёл до Астрахани и обратно это было
miracle of miracles. So there was a lot of things in the Soviet
чудо из чудес Так что много в Советском
Union
Союзе было
And what was the culture and What was the science
Чего А какая культура была а Какая наука
and
а
the military-industrial complex So there is Why I
ВПК Так что есть Почему
was bored I realized I wonder
скучал понял Интересно так
if you use medicines from
используете ли вы лекарства со стран
NATO countries I actually use Yes, it seems like there is something like that, either in
НАТО я вообще-то использую Да вроде как
Slovakia or
по что-то такое есть то ли Словакии то
something like that  There are pills
что-то такие какие-то таблетки есть А
Why does NATO need it if it wants to destroy
зачем НАТО если она хочет там уничтожить
Russia there? Why does it supply pills to
Россию зачем она поставляет таблетки в
Russia? Is this your question or is it mine?
России это твой вопрос или это мой мой
Well, what are you? Well, what is your question? Trade
ну а что ты Ну что ты вопрос ё торговля
is trade, I
есть торговлю
understand.
понял
So they ask Why Russians are prone to
Так спрашивают Почему русские склонны к
betrayal, here is the Vlasov army, a
предательству вот власовская армия
million Yes, people  had
миллион Да человек имела
and consisted mainly of Who were 80% were
а в составе в основном Кто был 80% были
Ukrainians in the Vlasov army so hello
украинцы во власовское армии так то алло
Russian liberation army no look
русская освободительная армия нет смотри
No no no So exactly 80%
Нет нет нет Так точно 80%
Ukrainians but but but you won’t tell me that
украинцы но но но ты мне это не
Well dadada yes Krylov’s fables
расскажешь Ну дадада да басни Крылова
so now
так сейчас
so 87 about  made up of
так вот 87 про составляли
Russians so there were also a few Tatars there
русские так были ещё там немного татар
were Belarusians 87 about the Russians what are
было белору 87 про русские какие
you talking about Ukrainians Cossacks Tatars and Cossacks
говоришь украинцы казаки татары и казаки
Yes  and then further Well, I
Да и тог дальше Ну я м по этому поводу
can say about this that I said that I
могу сказать что я сказал что я тебе
told you, I don’t deny this
сказал я от этого не отказываю
that you said that 80% were Ukrainians Yeah,
что ты сказал что 80% были украинцы Ага
Ukrainians Yes, and Vlasov’s army
украинцы Да уже и власовское армию
was attributed to
приписали
Ukraine and that they didn’t recruit gays unless they
Украине и что в геях не набирали разве
recruited Vlasov Ar  them or the question: You
Власов Ар набирали их или вопрос Вы
were born in the USSR, your nationality is
родились в СССР у вас национальность
SSC
ссц
Russian, and under the Soviet Union
русски а при Советском Союзе возник
such a community arose. Soviet man is a
такая общность Советский человек
man like this. Why did the Germans call
человек так Почему немцы называли
Russians
русских
ru? Well then  I can
ру Ну что я могу
say fascists and fascists Criminals and
сказать фашисты и фашисты Преступники и
criminals, well, how could they do
преступники ну как как они могли как
whatever they want Vyacheslav asks whether nails can be
угодно Вячеслав спрашивает гвозди ужели
used in Russia or not, beautiful
водить в России или нет прекрасный
waters at one time there was a mess, it’s not clear
вод одно время было заваруха непонятно
why now there
почему сейчас во здесь
are heaps in here Lady Forest says that in Russia
завались Леди лес говорит что в России
everything is built by Tajiks, they are
всё Таджики строят русские они в
mostly Russian  yes of course grandfather I agree
основном да конечно дед Согласен
So Maxim asks all villages have gas, I
Так Максим спрашивает газ во всех
think not
думаю что не во
all have it so where were they abroad
всех так где были за рубежом спрашивает
Victor asks talk Turkey Egypt
Виктор говорить Турция Египет
Greece they ask Kashpirovsky still
Греция спрашивают Кашпировский всё ещё
he treats people on television in
лечит людей на телевидении в
Russia
России проха
[ __ ] he treats there I don’t know the
пролы кого он там лечит Я не знаю
director of the distillery writes who is out of
директор спиртзавода пишет кто изле э
prison for
моли за
murder I can’t
убийство я не могу
say maybe
сказать может
[music]
[музыка]
Dostoevsky director of what the director of the
Достоевский директор чего директор
distillery is the nickname of such a
спиртзавода ник такой
person here in our aunt’s they bombed
человека вот у нас в тёткино разбомбили
the distillery Well, what an idiot  bombed the pepper
спиртзавод Ну какой идиот разбомбил перц
plant That's right, look, it's
завод Всё правильно да смотри это
called tarak Mada, a
называется тарак Мада территория
scorched Earth territory, we believe that the
выжженной Земли мы считаем что
Belgorod region
Белгородская область
supplies what 30 or 40% there
поставляет сколько там 30 или 40%
agricultural products on the
продукции сельскохозяйственной на
territory of Russia, chicken There and so
территории России курятина Там и так
on Yes, that’s all, and therefore an attack on this
дальше Да всё и поэтому атака на эту
infrastructure leads to a
инфраструктуру как раз приводит к
rise in prices and a shortage of these same eggs,
поднятию цен к нехватке этих же яиц
butter, that is, it raises social
масло то есть поднимает социальное
tension, therefore, using terror, the
напряжение поэтому методом террора
Ukrainian special services are burning out
украинские спецслужбы выжигают сельское
agriculture in the Belgorod region Yes, it’s
хозяйство в Белгородской области Да
cynical, but it’s  the war didn’t survive the war Well,
цинично но это война выжили не Ну вотже
yes, your butter is already disappearing with these
да уже масло у вас пропадает уже с эти
berries Kul
ягодня Кул
mas and we have a lot of chickens Nava
мас а кур у нас навалом курятина
That’s all but Well  Vram bh
Нава Вот вот вот всё но Ну что врам бх
are engaged in the EU I don’t
заниматся ЕС не
know Elizaveta is sewing And where is the science in
зна Елизавета сшивает А куда наука в
RUSI Why in the USSR was better than now
РОСИ Почему в ССР была лучше чем сейчас
in the World Cup the reason we have excellent science And
в ЧМ причина у нас прекрасная наука А
I understand But let’s say this now
понял А вот Давай скажем так сейчас
modern Russian science has come up with a
современная Российская наука придумала
thermonuclear reactor, not nuclear but a
термоядерный реактор не атомный а
thermonuclear one that works on
термоядерный который работает на
waste-free where  she Where is this reactor
безотходное где она Где этот реактор у
where is this reactor
вас где этот реактор у
you have a nuclear reactor 800 near Moscow in
вас ядерный реактор 800 под Москов
my opinion
по-моему
I don’t remember exactly he is the only Mini
Я точно не помню он единственный Мини
so far working on  without nuclear-free
пока работает на бездер безъядерного
waste without I understood, but Russian science
отхода без Поня понял а Российская наука
may have come up with a computer processor, at least
может придумала компьютер процессор хоть
something, a refrigerator,
что-то холодильник свой придумала
Russian science, I don’t know who
Российская наука я не знаю кто что
came up with what, we had it in bulk, in bulk Nuno,
придумал у нас это было навала навала
everything is shorter than Korean science,
нуно всё короче корейской науки
American science for some reason. Well, of course,
американской науки почему-то Ну конечно
yes, that’s what Lissner asks  why Russians are
да так лисснер спрашивает почему русские
not tolerant of other nations
не толерантно относятся к другим нациям
What kind of stupidity is this, but it’s
Что за глупость так есть но это
true Well, let it remain on the wall
правда Ну пускай о на стену
I was in Turkey
остаётся Я был в Турции
Turks
турки
men gold Earring in the
мужики золотая Серьга в
ear  they pack me in a parachute and
ухе запаковывают меня в парашут и на
go up 200m, this is a miracle
200м уходит наверх вот это турки чудо
tour from the Turks. What do you think: When was
тур Как вы считаете Когда было
life better in the USSR or in the Russian
лучше жилось в СССР или в Российской
Federation? Well, it had its own thing And here it has its own Well,
Федерации Ну там было своё А тут своё Ну
where is it better after all? Well, what does it mean? It
где лучше всё-таки Ну что значит
was better then among the people in Soviet  The
Лучше тогда был у людей в Советском
Union had a healthy morale, it
Союзе был здоровый моральный дух
was healthy, and now, what is money,
здоровый был так А сейчас что деньги
money, material prices, and what is the
деньги материальный цен А что из
positive thing you have there now, and what is the
позитива сейчас у вас там а а из
positive thing, what do you have now? I
позитива Что там у вас сейчас
mean, well, well, it was better in the Soviet Union
В смысле Ну хорошо в Советском Союзе
because it was  morale
лучше было потому что был моральный дух
And what’s better in Russia
А чем лучше в России
now, yes, I wouldn’t say that
сейчас да я бы не сказал что
life is better, it’s just changed, that it’s
лучше жизнь просто изменилась что сейчас
better now in Russia than it was in the Soviet
лучше в России чем было в Советском
Union, Yes, life is not
Союзе Да не лучше жизнь Ну смотрите в
better. Well, look, morale was better in the Soviet Union,
Советском Союзе лучший был моральный дух
so what’s better in Russia now than it was?
так А что сейчас лучше в России чем было
in the union again
в союзе опять
Let's continue like
Давай дальше
this, so the grandfather wants to sit on two chairs and the
так так дед на два стула хочет сесть и
cool scoop writes like this
совок крутой так
Was he in the
пишет Был ли в
USSR? Well, in the program later when there was
СССР Ну в передаче позд когда был
a teleconference, one woman still
телемост одна женщина до сих пор же это
remember this in the Soviet Union says they laughed until they
помни Советском Союзе говорит ржали до
dropped and  We’re still laughing
упаду и до сих пор смеёмся
Well, people were like you
Ну люди были какой то ты в Советском
weren’t in the Soviet Union This is the woman Roman
Союзе не было Вот такая женщина Роман
asks Gazprom records record
спрашивает Газпром фиксирует рекордные
losses on television They say that sanctions
убытки в телевизия говорят что санкции
only help How do you relate to this
только помогают Как вы к этому отнесёте
that sanctions, well, they tell you from
что санкции ну э вас говорят с
TV that sanctions are only
телевизора что санкции идут только на
beneficial Yes  but at the same time, Gazprom
пользу Да но в то же время Газпром
records large losses Why is
фиксирует большие убытки Почему
this so And where does this data from your
так А откуда эти данные с вашего
TV come from? It’s not with Gazprom. Everything is fine with us. The
телевизора нене с газпромом У нас всё в
sanctions are going on, but Gazprom is in decline.
порядке санкции идут а Газпром с убылью
Record  decline record
Рекордная убыль рекордный
loss Well, let
убыток Ну пускай думает
Elena Mostovaya think so about the Soviet Union
Так Елена Мостовая про Советский Союз
asking to pay bribes to buy
спрашивает платить взятки чтобы купить
scarce furniture or household appliances
дефицит ную мебель или бытовую технику
This is a strong
Это крепкий моральный
morale there were problems with foreign furniture
дух с мебелью зарубежной были проблемы
Well, this does not mean that we did not have
Ну это не значит что у нас не было
furniture beds chairs
мебели кровате стульев
tables lava furniture Yugoslav wall
столов лавская мебель Югославская стенка
or  GDR or the Madonna service, how come
или ГДР или сервиз Мадонна как ну как же
Mikhail Mikhail asks how long
Миха Михаил спрашивает сколько Вы ещё
will you keep the Mummy in the
будете Мумию держать в
Mausoleum when I tell him  I’ll report
Мавзолее когда Я ему я ему доложу
when they
когда так
say so, Yes,
ээ говорят Да совсем зарубеж ко всему
there were queues for everything foreign, there were queues with it, there were
зарубежному стояли очереди с ним было
all the problems, I didn’t understand anything, in short, everything
все проблемы ничего не понял Короче всё
foreign in the Soviet Union was in
зарубежное в Советском Союзе было в
short supply behind them, there were queues Yes, there were
дефиците за ними стояли очереди Да было
shortages and they say these problems were with
дефициты и говорят эти проблемы были со
all goods, not only with
всем товаром не только с мебелью
foreign furniture  the goods are not Yes cool asks
зарубежные товар не Да круч спрашивает
why in an Orthodox country on the
почему в православной стране на
square they went further with a difficult question
площади пошли дальше тяжёлый вопрос
Yes not Putin’s question will be put in the Mausoleum
Да не вопрос Путина положат в Мавзолей
together with
вме вместе с
Lenin Let’s continue like this Suren
Лениным Давай дальше так Сурен
ask the children of the war in Germany
спрашивают дети войны в Германии
get  3,000 euros and a full
получают 3.000 евро и полный пакет
social package And in Russia, it’s
социальный А в России
[ __ ] where they
фигню то где
respect the participants in the victory over Nazism in
уважают участников победы над нацизмом в
Germany or in
Германии или в
Russia What I respect, look in Germany
России Что уважаю смотрите в Германии
Children of war Yes, they get 3,000 euros and a
Дети войны Да получают 3.000 евро и
full social package And what do
полный социальный пакет А что получают
children get in And what kind of Children of
дети во А что за Дети
war are those who are those  who
войны те кто те кто во время Второй
grew up during the Second World War turns out to be children,
мировой войны росли получается детьми
there are like you now have pensioners
есть как вот увас сейчас пенсионеры
who during the war were children
которые во время войны были детьми
somewhere in factories Well, they’re going to the hall like
где-то на заводах Ну им зала идт как
How long is it going to my neighbor at home I
Сколько идёт у меня вот по домой соседка
don’t
не
know,
знаю
they ask awkwardly  Well, it’s going
неловко спрашивают ну идёт
like this
угу так
Why so long, well, wait a historian, now
Почему столько ну подожди историк теперь
I’m you, but still answer
я те ви но всё-таки ответь
who hoisted the flag of victory over the stam
кто флаг побед водрузил над стам
And you, I’m trolling you Well, someone there from the
А те я тебя тролли Ну кто-то там из
Soviet that everyone heard so that everyone from the
Советского что все слышали чтобы все из
Soviet Union is some kind of Georgian kantari
Советского Союза какой-то кантари грузин
And  What did you tell me, I was trolling you that I’m
А ты мне что говорил я тебя троллил что
American, I’m
Американ я
trolling, well then, dear, tell me what was
троли а ну тогда Родной скажи а что было
signed in Berlin in Berlin first,
подписано в Берлине в Берлине сначала
then look first, it was signed in
значит смотри сначала э подписано было в
there in France, it wasn’t  look,
там во Франции было это не смотри
first it was signed in France, then
сначала подписано во Франции было потом
Stalin said that Let’s sign with
Сталин сказал что Давайте ещё подпишем с
us and signed in Berlin, it was already there, yes, the
нами и подписали в Берлине уже был да
Soviet Union was already in Berlin, signed,
Советский Союз уже в Берлине подписывал
yes, on May 9, who on Not the ninth of the eighth, it
да 9 мая кто по Не девятого восьмого это
was the eighth, it was the ninth, it was the eighth,
восьмого было девятого это восьмого было
Well, the fifth Well, now Rani  it was
Ну а пятый Ну вот сейчас Рани было
European so according to European time
Европейское так по европейскому времени
there
там
at the place of signing So I was trolling you
на по месту подписания Так я же тебя
then I was trolling you Yes I was brazenly trolling
тогда я троллил тебя Да я нагло троллил
so I made you emotional Yes I am a troll
так выводил тебя на эмоцию Да троли я
trolled everything
троллил всё
fairly won Well, the Americans won,
честно победили Ну американцы победили в
including you, not the Anti-Hitler
том числе вы не Антигитлеровская
coalition Soviet Union Americans
коалиция Советский Союз американцы
British since what year They where they were until
британцы со чего года Они где были до
forty, they fought too, and where with the
соро чет воевали они тоже да где с
Americans where they fought of course they fought and the
Американ где воевали конечно воевали а
Soviet Union until and the Soviet Union until the
Советский Союз до а Советский Союз до
forty-first year where  was Wait, where did the
Сорок первого года где был Подожди где
Americans fight until Forty, what where did they
американцы воевали до Сорок чего где
fight and at sea who fought with
воевали а на море кто воевал с
Hitler Americans?
Гитлером американцы
Come on, [ __ ],
Да давай
you’re all Ukrainians  heard that the flag
сри так украинцы вы все слышали что флаг
at the Resta ru lived Berest Yegorov and
на реста ру жили берест Егоров и
Cantaria the surrender of Germany was under
кантария капитуляция Германии была под
look United on May 8, I won’t deceive The
смотри Соединённые 8 мая не обману
United States of America entered the
Соединённые Штаты Америки вступили во
Second World War on December 7,
Вторую мировую войну 7 декабря сорок
1941 Where did they join Where are you from
года как они Где они вступили Откуда ты
again Well, look, I took it
вот ещё раз Ну вот смотри я вот взял
Wikipedia USA in World War II The
Википедии США во Второй мировой войне
United States of America entered
Соединённые Штаты Америки вступили во
World War II on December 7,
Вторую мировую войну 7 декабря сорок
1941 for the first time since
года первый раз вот после нападения
Japanese attacks on Pearl Harbor attacks, here the USA
Японии на Перл Харбор атаки вот США
declared war, look, the USA declared
объявила войну на смотри США объявила
war on Japan and Nazi Germany and
войну Японии а нацистская Германия и
fascist Italy declared war on the USA, all
фашистская Италия объявили войну США всё
from the year 1941, the USA fought with
с сорок первого года США воевала с
Germany with Germany Yes, with the Japanese Yes,
Германией с Германией Да с японцами А да
yes, yes I confused I thought with Russia Yes
это да Я перепутал Я думал с Россией Да
yes yes it was Well that’s all what you’re
да да это было Ну это всё то что ты
talking about with Japan Well ish Germany
говоришь с Японией Ну иш с Германией
also fought And in the Atlantic in the Atlantic
воевала тоже А в Атлантике в Атлантике
how many German ships were sunk And
сколько потоплено кораблей немецких А
how many planes  shot down by the USA where
сколько самолётов сбило США где Вот
Look, open Wikipedia Yes And now
смотри открываешь Википедии Да И вот
there is the Pacific theater of military
есть Тихоокеанский театр военных
operations, the Mediterranean theater of military
действий средиземноморский театр военных
operations, the Western European theater of
действий западноевропейский театр э
military operations, everything
военных действий вот всё
is there except the Pacific
есть кроме Тихоокеанского Смотри вот те
Look here and see how many Americans
зано и посмотри сколько американцев
died in the war, so look, on
погибло в войне так вот смотри э 8
November 8, 1942, the American
ноября сорок второго года американские
troops under the command of General
войска под командование Генерала
Eisenhower, three corps of the West
эйзенхауэра три корпуса Западной
Central and East, with the support of
Центральной Восточный при поддержке
British aircraft, landed on the
британской авиации высадились на
Atlantic coast of Morocco
Атлантическом побережье Марокко
Mediterranean coast of Algeria And so
средиземноморском побережье Алжир И так
on the corps fought fully, what do you
дальше полноценно воевали корпуса что ты
start saying and you say how many
начинаешь говорить а ты говоришь сколько
died, look you need to look at the contribution not
погибло смотри нужно смотреть вклад не
by the number of dead, yes So look
по количеству погибших да Так посмотри
how many of them died, so look
сколько их погибло так вот смотри Почему
Why why died because Stalin and the
почему погибло потому что Сталин и жуков
Soviet people didn’t count the beetles as now
людей советских не считали как сейчас
as  now Putin doesn’t count Yes, why did the
как сейчас Путин не считает Да почему
Americans fight so that few of theirs
американцы воевали так чтобы ихние мало
died, you understand? I
гибли понимаешь
understand, but the Soviet Union
Поня а сове а Советский Союз вот так
threw them like that Yes, my grandfather told me Yes,
закидывал Да у меня дед рассказывал Да
they drove them away  so in short, one rifle for
гнали их вот так короче одна винтовка на
three, someone falls, the second picks up
трёх кто-то падает второй поднимает
the rifle, that’s how it happened This man is
винтовку вот так было Этот человек вам
lying to you, he’s lying I’ve
врёт врёт Я
never been a stockist and he was born in
в никогда не был стком и Родился он в
Poland, never believe this
Польше никогда не верьте этому
man, you can now check on Wikipedia
человеку ты можешь сейчас в Википедии
Where Bandera was born, he’s not in
проверить Где родился Бандера он не в
Poland  born and in Austria Hungary Well yes I
Польше родился а в Австрии Венгрии Ну да
see okay There are also questions about the
Понятно ладно Ещё вопросы есть так про
USA you also briefly about this about
США ты тоже короче про это про
so further sheet Who
так дальше лист Кто
received the Soviet Union from whom America
получал Советский Союз от кого Америки
without America you would have defeated Hitler Well
без Америки вы бы победили Гитлера Ну
you know  it would be right away right away yes Zabka yes
знаешь бы это бы сразу сразу да забка да
Roman asks Why aren’t you
Роман спрашивает А почему вас не
interested in what was signed on the eighth in
интересует что было подписано восьмого в
Paris on the seventh in Paris Well, how can I
Париже седьмого в Париже Ну это как вам
tell you it was there and France signed
сказать там была и Франция подписывала
Yes the British signed France she where
Да англичане подписывали Франция она где
she that she fought she took part in the war at
она что воевала она участие в войне при
Well of course she
Ну конечно
took part  from the very beginning she took
принимала с самого начала принимала
part in the war, she guarded
участие в войне она охраняла
Hitler’s bunker. Wait a minute,
гитлеровский бункер Подождите ещё
France was still at war with Germany when the
Франция воевала ещё с Германией когда
Soviet Union sat back and helped
Советский Союз отсиживаться и помогал
Germany, the
Германии было
Germans were there when look like this C  in
немцы когда так смотри С тридцать
1939, Germany was at war when the
девятого года Германия воевала когда
Soviet Union was still supplying Hitler,
Советский Союз ещё поставлял Гитлеру
helping him on and on And so the French
помогал так дальше А так французы
guarded Hitler’s bunker until the very end
охраняли бункер Гитлера до самого
[music]
[музыка]
so,
последнего так
so, of course the regiment was Normandy, not dumb, the
так-так конечно полк был норманди не
pilots had resistance in
неме лётчики сопротивление было во
France. Well, it was all so
Франции Ну это всё было настолько мало
small, so traitorous  Fri general, well, what does the
чка так предатель птн генерал ну что
battle say, uh, you had a traitor,
говорит боя э так У вас был предатель
General Vlasov. And what? Well, how many
генерал Власов И что Ну что Сколько
million of your Vlasovites fought? Yes,
миллион власовцев ваших воевало Да
let’s give it. Why is there a
так давайте дать Да почему в СССР
radio factory worker in the USSR?  couldn’t buy a radio
рабочий радиозавода не мог купить радио
and he had to steal it couldn’t buy
и ему пришлось его украсть не мог купить
what
чего
radio what radio Well, the worker who
радио какого радио Ну рабочий который
made the radio at the radio factory why
изготавливал радио на радиозаводе почему
couldn’t he buy the
он не мог купить
radio how couldn’t he buy where I couldn’t
радио как не мог купить где я не мог
buy Okay, some
купить Ладно приехали какие-то
questions arrived Bush’s legs definitely ate in the nineties  I
вопросы ножки Буша ели в девяностых
still remember this kind of grass,
обязательно такая трава до сих пор помню
well, they ate it. Yes, and the whole Soviet
ну ели Да так е е так весь Советский
Union, including the Ukrainians, ate it, they ate it, and they were
Союз в том числе и украинцы ели так ели
cracking right behind their ears. The
что Аж за ушами трещали
Russians were screaming that they  Heirs of the
так русские кричат что они Наследники
Winners and Ukrainians Heirs of the
Победителей а украинцы Наследники
Winners Well, in the form they are now, of
Победителей Ну в таком виде как сейчас
course No, I mean no, look here,
конечно Нет в смысле нет смотри у нас
if you look at the number of
если ты посмотришь по количеству как раз
Soviet citizens who died in World War II, most of them are
советских граждан то большинство из них
Ukrainians, in every village we have huge ones,
украинцев у нас в каждом селе огромные
just these memorial plaques  with
просто вот эти памятные плиты с
surnames so it’s not necessary, what did you do
фамилиями так что не надо что вы сделали
with the monument to the horse? Well, why did they take it,
с памятником ко коне Да ну брали зачем
the occupiers, who is Konev,
оккупанты кто такой Конев
would have had the sign of the kopak cap too In short
бы при зна копака колпака тоже Короче
look Kovpak it’s like motoro Girkin
смотри Ковпак это как моторо гиркин
you understand those times it’s a
понимаешь тех врем это
commune street from our territory Armed Forces our
комуни ули с нашей територии ВС наши
people Yes they shed blood yes And your these
люди Да проливали кров да А ваши эти
Commissars only went here
Комиссары только тут ездили
in short
короче
what the detachment consisted of I have no idea it’s
что состоял отряд Понятия не имею это
all collaborators red
всё это коллаборанты красные
collaborators USA don’t listen to your grandfather don’t
коллаборанты США не слушайте деда не
listen
слуша
Why not  Well, why are you starting
Зачем бо ну зачем ты это начинаешь
to throw this at my listeners? Well, I see. Well,
накидывать моим слушателям Ну понятно Ну
why am I telling them lies here,
зачем я их тут им неправду рассказываю
you’ll tell them the truth now like this  No need
ты им сейчас правду скажешь так Не надо
Let’s do it like that,
Давай всё-таки так
uh, well,
ээ так так
well, do you know the settlement of Lokot
так знаете ли вы населённый пункт локоть
and the Lokot
и локотской
Republic? This means the Bryansk region.
Республику Это имеется в виду брянщина
Yes, well, Hey, what was it like, how do you feel
Да ну Слыш что было такое как относитесь
about the joint parade of Russian and German
к совместному параду русских и немецких
Nazis in
нацистов в
Brest? Well, rudely, where is this, who saw
Бресте Ну что грубо где это кто видел
thirty  ninth year so there are photos
тридцать девятый год так есть фотографии
Yes, I watched the video there is a video And what Well
Да я смотрел ролик ролик есть И что Ну
what a parade three cars are carrying a gun the
что какой парад три машины везут орудие
Germans are leaving ours are coming what a parade
немцы уходят наши приходят какой парад
parade there are these officials  they stand Yes,
парад там эти официальные лица стоят Да
what kind of official ones would the general stand in command
какие официальные ли бы командую стоял
and our
генерал и наш
Colonel and three guns left? And ours,
Полковник и три пушки уехало А наши
in short, with the Germans by the hands there are thin bom
короче с немцами за ручки там тонки бом
Yes of course of
Да конечно
course so Prigozhin is a hero or traitors
конечно так Пригожин герой или предатели
Why I have no idea
Почему без понятия не знаю так
if Stalin is a commu
является ли Сталин комму
nafa Let's continue why the Great Russian
нафа Давай дальше почему Великая русская
culture has not made Russians people
культура не сделала из россиян людей
capable of living in peace and harmony with
способных жить в мире и согласие и с
themselves and with the world. Good
собой и с миром Хороший
question. Well, actually, if you look at it,
вопрос Ну вообще-то если разобраться
Russia has never lived in peace;
Россия никогда не жила в мире всегда на
someone has always attacked Russia; therefore, or periods
Россию кто-то нападал поему или периоды
less than 30 years, Russia has always been
менее 30 лет всегда Россия с кем-то
at war with someone Not because Russia attacked
воевала Не потому что Россия нападала на
Russia, that is, Georgia attacked Russia
Россия то есть Грузия напала на Россию
Ukraine attacked Russia Everyone attacks
Украина напала на Россию Все нападают
Finland, look Finland
Финляндия смотрите Финляндия в тридцать
attacked Russia in 1939, then
девятом напала на Россию потом Латвия
Latvia Lithuania Estonia attacked Russia Poland
Литва Эстония напала на Россию Польша
attacked Russia Estonia  the war was well
напала на Россию эстони война была ну
attacked Yes they attacked and as a result
напала Да напали и в результате
they captured Russia and made the Soviet
захватили Россию и сделали Советский
Union join in general join
Союз присоединились вообще присоединись
attacked and joined a cool move
напали и присоединились прикольный ход
Yes, well, on the question Do you have a bomb shelter,
Да ну по вопрос У вас бомбоубежище есть
that there is a bomb shelter
что бомбоубежище
Well, in the houses there is the most interesting thing, they are
есть Ну в домах есть самое интересное
standing at bus stops, they are concrete How to
стоят на остановках это бетонные Как
say the boxes Uh-huh, the question is
сказать коробки Угу по настани вопрос
how did it happen that Germany
как так получилось что Германия
lost uh but
проиграла э но
uh Pen are rich And we are poor and we are
ээ Пен богатые А мы бедные и у нас
wonderfully rich, we are all  we have no
прекрасно богатые мы всё у нас есть не
worse than the Soviet Union, and that is, it
хуже чем Советский Союз да то есть
turns out that a German in Germany had a
получается немец в Германии имел
Normal life, but the Soviet Union
Нормальную жизнь а Советском Союзе даже
didn’t even have enough goods. Why is this so? Why did the
товаров не хватало Почему так Почему
winners live worse than
победители жили хуже
the vanquished? This is a rhetorical question  So
побеждённых Это вопрос риторический Так
why was it normal that we lived in
почему нормально мы жили в
Sovetskoye in Germany they gave us free
Советском в Германии давали бесплатные
apartments Well look for some reason
квартиры Ну смотри почему-то
then after
пото после
that a huge number of them came here from Germany
тогой огромное количество они с Германии
why Well first of all the Germans left no the
почему Ну во-первых уехали немцы нет
Russians also but both the Germans and the Russians left
русские тоже по уезжал и немцы и русски
So why if it’s like that here  it was good
Так а почему если тут так было хорошо
why they left and not from Germany,
почему они уехали а не с Германии полит
they thought it was better there for some reason, but
они посчитали там лучше почему-то да вот
now with Pugach she left the jackdaw. Well, what can I
сейчас с Пугач уехала с галки Ну что я
say [music] how do you feel about the fact that you’ve grown
сказать как относитесь к тому что врос
up?  they put Buyanova, a pediatrician, in jail because a
лет посадили в врача педиатра буянову за
visitor reported on her that she seemed to be
донесла посетительница что она вроде там
saying something against
что-то говорила против
the army, what did she say? Okay, I understand. Let's
армии что она говорила Ладно понял
go to the question of who attacked Russia in the
Поехали вопрос кто напал на Россию в
First World
Первой мировой
War. Well, you're a historian, so it
войне Ну и вот ты же историк так Россия
turns out that Russia attacked. But who
получается напала Да а кто
Prince Ferb is not not Feuerbach but Franz
принца Ферба не не феербаха а Франца
Ferdinand
фердинан
Ferdinan who is his Rila principle
фердинан кто его Рила принцип
burn Sarajevo Bosnian Bosnia talked about the
гори Сараева боснийский босни говорил о
principle shot the Austrian Franz
принцип застрелил австрийского Франца
Ferdinand Yes  because of this, Austria
фердинанда Да из-за этого Австрия
declared war on Serbia and Russia Why did it
гласила войну Сербии а Россия Зачем
attack other
напала на другие
countries
страны
gory And how did Russia end up in the First
гори А как Россия попала в Первую
World
мировую
War because the West moved towards Russia
войну потому запад двинуться на Россию
no no stop stop Austria attacked
нет нет стоп стоп Австрия напала на
Serbia declared war and Russia and that’s
сербию объявила войну а Россия причём
all and Serbia stopped like that and Russia
всё и Сербия остановилась так а Россия
Moreover  then just wait they attacked Serbia
Причём тут так подожди напали на сербию
and that’s the end of it Yes no no How
и на этом остановку Да нет нет А как
was Russia I’m asking how Russia
Россия было Я спрашиваю как Россия
got into the war so
попала в войну так
I’m so angry about Russia  attacked no so Russia
я так на Россию напали нет так Россия
declared war and started to fight
объявила войну и начала воевать
I was the first world yes yes look Russia yes I
я первая миро да да вот смотри Россия
think Russia even she kind of started
да помоему Россия даже она ж типа начала
yes like she started joining like
да типа она начала вступать типа типа
Alya for Serbia there against Austria
Аля за сербию там на Австрию Да
Yes, the Russian Empire entered the
вот вот Российская империя вступила в
First World War on August 1  Chena of the year
Первую мировую войну 1 августа Чена года
in the country of
на стране
Antan
антан
So let's see
Так давай вот посмотрим
Well, Troll, well, no, it
Ну и Троль ну не ну так правильно
turns out right, you say that
получается ты ты же говоришь что всегда
Russia has always been attacked
на Россию нападали
Well, the role is like that in the murder of chi
Ну роль вот так в убийстве чи
Austria-Hungary announced presented an
австро-венгрия объявила предъявила
ultimatum to Serbia like this The Russian Empire
Сербии Ультиматум так Российская империя
announced general mobilization That is,
объявила всеобщую мобилизацию То есть у
Austria-Hungary and Serbia have the Balkans Yes,
австро-венгрии с сербией это Балканы Да
some graters Russia announces The
какие-то тёрки Россия объявляет
Russian Empire announces general
Российская империя объявляет всеобщую
mobilization
мобилизацию
So, well, the Serbs have always been friends of
Так так ну Сербы всегда были друзьями
Russia and the Serbs are still friends of Russia
России и до сих пор Сербы друзья России
so Okay, let's move
так Окей едем
on to the question: Why didn't this inventor of
дальше вопрос Почему этот изобретатель
Katyusha Zhora Langemak see the Victory Parade on
Катюши Жора лангемак не увидел Парад
May 9th?  data from some Zhora Lang It’s
мая такие данные какой-то Жоры Ланг
interesting that behind me, it seems he was
Интересно что за мне гори кажется его
probably shot, yes yes, because
расстреляли наверное да да его Потому
he was shot in 1938,
что его в тридцать восьмом году
the first I heard was on
расстреляли первый слышал прож да по по
false charges of sabotage and
ложному обвинению во вредительство и
participation in an anti-Soviet deed. Yes, the
участие в антисоветской де Да
inventor of Katyusha, it turns out he was
изобретателя Катюши да получается
shot in 1938
расстреляли в тридцать восьмом
so you know Sasha Prokhorov from Rostov, I don’t
так Сашу Прохорова из Ростова знаете не
know
я знаю
Sasha
Сашу
Ivanova,
Иванову
I understand Who built the Baikalo-Amur
понял Кто построил байкалоамурскую
highway asks the
магистраль спрашивает
Komsomol from which country from which
Комсомол с какой страны с каких
republics of the Soviet Union so that is
республик советского так то есть
it turns out that all the Komsomol Republics
получается что все Республики Комсомол
from all the republics built the
со всех республик построил русским
Baikalo-Amur highway for the Russians
байкалоамурскую магистраль
Yes Dada
Да Дада
and you are not grateful we built for you we built for you
а вы не благодарны мы вам строили мы вам
you are not grateful
строили вы не благодарны аййй
ayyyyyyyyyyyyyyyyyyyyyyyyyyyyyyyyyyyyyyyyyyyyyyyyyyy And
так так так давайте е сжи пожалуйста А
where did you get the Kharkov
откуда у вас взялся Харьковский
Tractor
тракторный
Plant built by us
завод построили мы построили
built built by our Ukrainians
построили построили наши украинцы
built Who built the
построили Кто построил
Ukrainians More than that, our Ukrainians
украинцы Боше того м наши украинцы
went to Tyumen for you And so on they built
ездили вам в Тюмень И так дальше строили
the entire oil industry for you  he came to Ukraine
всю нефтянку вам как он на Украину попал
and look, I’ll
а посмотри
read it and moreover, look how much you
прочитаю и больше того смотри сколько вы
took from Ukraine, learned teachers from us,
забирали из Украины у нас учёных
took you to Moscow to
преподавателей забирали себе в Москву в
Leningrad Yes, damn it, and then right away
Ленинград Да вот блин и потом сразу вот
there are
там
universities there, damn it, and we built you, bam,
университеты блин а мы вам построили бам
we built you the entire oil industry, Gazprom, the
мы вам всю нефтянку Газпром это всё
Ukrainians built it all  Ukrainians, Kazakhs and
украинцы строили украинцы казахи и
Azerbaijanis, that’s where the oil industry was,
азербайджанцы вот там г нефтянка была
where did you get the Yuzhmash tractor,
так во откуда вас взялся трактор южмаш
Kuchma actually
Кучма вообще
built it  Well, everyone knows Kuchma like he is the
построил Ну Кучма все знают типа он Это
father of Yuzhmash and Antonov’s factories
отец южмаша а заводы Антонова самол
were built by Antonov. It’s clear, that’s why
построил Понятно ну поэтому
Yes, we brought electricity to
Да электричество принесли мы вам на
Russia and technology brought the Internet,
Россию да технологии принесли интернет
now they brought it, listen, that’s the
сейчас принесли слушай-ка Вот вот а
most ancient people in the world,
какой самый древний народ в мире
Ukrainians, Ukrainians, that’s correct Listen,
украинцы украинцы правильно это Слушай а
why  Ukrainians do not believe that Ukrainians are the
почему украинцы не верит что украинцы
most ancient people, but because yes,
самый древний народ а потому что да
because during the Soviet Union, Yes,
Потому что во время Советского Союза Да
we were fooled by
нас оболванивание
this correct theory, and the French
этой правильной теории А французские
they are also gals
галы они тоже у
in the village of Stepan Bandera, just from there the
в селе Степана Бандеры как раз оттуда
flock is from there the Ugrians from there the gals came from the Pope
стаю Угры оттуда галы пошли Папа Римский
no Rum and Rum they are sums not not sums
нет Ром и Рому они сумщины не не сумщины
they are from the mill region not this is not from the
они с мельницкой области не это не с
city of Romny not in the sum the city of Romny this is
города Ромны не в суме город Ромны это
another Sumy
другое Сумской
region I am more more than that  I’ll say,
области я больше больше того скажу Вот
look Jesus, he was Who he was, a
смотри Иисус он был Кто он был
Galilean, also a Galician, not he was a
галилеянин тоже галичанин не он был
Ukrainian, Well, that’s right, Because from
украинец Ну Правильно Потому что с
Galicia, Well  Galicians he is a Galilean Jesus
галиции Ну галичи он галилеянин Иисус
was a Galilean
галилеянин был так
so the Black Sea We also dug up yes And
что Чёрное море Мы тоже выкопали да А
when you dripped into the Black Sea throw it away
когда вы капали в чёрно море откидывать
from the mines onto the Crimean Mountains so the
от коп на Крымские горы таким образом
Crimean Mountains appeared Yes
Крымские горы появились Да
I Well, what else do we end like this even further
я Ну что ещё так заканчиваем ещё дальше
Nope, what else is of interest Let us tell you all the myths
нене что ещё интересу Давай все мифы
you know that all the myths
расскажи какие ты знаешь что все мифы
that you know Tell
которые ты знаешь Расскажи
me what I’ll say Look, the Ukrainians
я вот что скажу Смотри украинцы
built Moscow, the Ukrainians will destroy it
построили Москву украинцы её и уничтожат
Let's get it done for today, let's get on with this Note, we had a
Давай на сегодня всё давай на этой Ноти
good talk with the Belgorod grandfather. Of
так с белгородским дедом хорошо
course, he's always an
поговорили Э он конечно всегда
interesting weirdo. Yes, so let's like
интересный Чудик Да так давайте лайк
subscribe comment write to th Telegram directly at
подписка комент пись на й Telegram прям
once axis VN
зараз ось ВН
apok tse more and more respectfully YouTube taking
апок це дуже и дуже важливо YouTube заня
us through the ORV srg to your ban and
нас через срг ОРВ в твый бан и дуже
I don’t show too many videos to people at all times, I don’t
багато вдео не показую людям вчасно не
show information about streams for this
показуе информация про стримы тому для
reason  Shchob mi Mali operational link ppi
того щоб ми Мали оперативный звязок ппи
right now and while there in telegra okm
прямо зараз а пок там в телегра окм
video
видео ще
shchekava and korisna information and we will
цикава и корисна информация и мы повинни
blame you trimati postiyny operational
з вами тримати постийний оперативный
link
звязок
nezalezhno in that chi show you the process
незалежно в того чи покаже вам проце
YouTube Glory to Ukraine
YouTube Слава украини
subscribe L
подпишись L